Gluttony. Greed. Sloth. Envy. Wrath. Pride. Lust.
Se7en is a crime, mystery, thriller film directed by David Fincher.
Two homicide detectives are on a desperate hunt for a serial killer whose crimes are based on the "seven deadly sins"
in this dark and haunting film that takes viewers from the tortured remains of one victim to the next.
The seasoned Det.
Somerset researches each sin in an effort to get inside the killer's mind, while his
novice partner, Mills, scoffs at his efforts to unravel the case.
Somerset, played by Morgan Freeman.
Mills, played by Brad Pitt.
Tracy, played by Gwyneth Paltrow.
Officer Davis, played by John Cassini.
Dr. O'Neill, played by Peter Crombie.
Dr. Santiago, played by Reg E. Cathey.
Seven (often stylized as Se7en) is a 1995 American crime thriller film
directed by David Fincher and written by Andrew Kevin Walker.
It stars Brad Pitt and Morgan Freeman, with Gwyneth Paltrow and John C.
McGinley in supporting roles.
Set in an unnamed, crime-ridden city, the narrative follows disenchanted, nearly retired Detective Lieutenant William Somerset and his newly
transferred partner David Mills as they try to stop a serial killer from committing a series of murders based on the seven deadly sins.
Walker, an aspiring writer, based Seven on his experiences of moving from a suburban setting to
New York City during a period of rising crime and drug addiction in the late 1980s.
An Italian film company optioned his script, but following financial
difficulties, the rights were sold to New Line Cinema.
Studio executives were opposed to the script's bleak conclusion,
insisting on a more mainstream and optimistic outcome.
Fincher, determined to re-establish himself after a career setback with his directorial debut Alien 3 (1992), was mistakenly sent Walker's
original script and, convinced of its merit, committed to directing the project if the original ending remained intact.
Principal photography took place in Los Angeles between December
1994 and March 1995, on a $33–34 million budget.
Seven garnered middling test audience results and was not predicted to
perform well due to its violent and mature content.
However, it grossed $327 million worldwide, becoming a sleeper hit
and the seventh highest-grossing film of the year.
Contemporaneous reviews were generally positive, praising the
performances of the central cast and the ending.
Seven revitalized Fincher's career and helped Pitt move from roles
based on his appearance to more serious, dramatic roles.
In the years since its release, the critical reception has been more positive.
The film has inspired a number of television series and
films with its aesthetic, music, and premise.
Its title sequence, which depicts the killer preparing for his actions in the film, is considered an important design innovation that sparked a renewed
interest in title design, while the film's twist ending has been named as one of the most shocking and unforgettable in cinematic history.
The film explores themes of rage and hate, police,
s.w.a.t., sadism, self-fulfilling prophecy.
The tone is intense and dark and mind_bending.